In the last quiz, you figured out which select clauses you'd need to
في الاختبار الأخير، اكتشفتم عبارات select التي ستحتاجون إليها
do some particular queries.
لإنشاء بعض الاستعلامات المحددة.
Now let's do one of those queries in SQL.
والآن، لنقم بإنشاء أحد تلك الاستعلامات في SQL.
It's time to take attendance at the zoo.
وقد حان وقت الحضور إلى حديقة الحيوانات.
We need to know how many of each species we have, and
حيث يلزمنا معرفة كم عدد كل فصيلة موجودة لدينا
it would be a big help if we had the most popular species listed first.
وستكون مساعدة كبيرة أن يتم سرد الفصائل الأكثر شيوعًا أولًا.
Because, they'll take the most time for the zookeepers to count.
وذلك لأن حرّاس حديقة الحيوانات سيستغرقون معظم الوقت في عدّها.
We've put a cheat sheet of all the select clauses we've seen so
ولقد وضعنا ورقة تذكير لجميع عبارات select التي رأيناها حتى الآن
far, in the instructor notes below the editor on the next page.
في ملاحظات المعلم أسفل المحرر في الصفحة التالية.
But, you have to put them together correctly,
ولكن ينبغي لكم جمعها بطريقة صحيحة
into a query that makes sense.
في استعلام منطقي.
Feel free to take a few tries, using the test round button.
فلا تترددوا في إجراء بعض المحاولات باستخدام الزر test round.
You'll see the result table down below.
وسترون جدول النتائج أدناه.
When you've got it, press Submit,
وعند الانتهاء، اضغطوا على الزر Submit،
and your query will be tested against a larger database.
وسيتم فحص الاستعلام مقابل قاعدة بيانات كبيرة.
So here's the problem.
إذن ها هي المسألة.
Write a query that returns all the species in the zoo, and how many animals
اكتبوا استعلامًا يستدعي جميع الفصائل في حديقة الحيوانات، وكم عدد الحيوانات
of each species there are, sorted with the most populous species at the top.
من كل فصيلة موجودة، المصنفة بأنها في مقدمة الفصائل الأكثر شيوعًا.
And here's an example, if the zoo had 4 gorillas, 2 alpaca,
وإليكم هذا المثال، إذا كانت حديقة الحيوانات بها 4 غوريلات واثنين من حيوان الألبكة
1 brown bear and no other animals, then we'd get a result like this.
ودب بني واحد ولا يوجد حيوانات أخرى، فإننا نحصل على نتيجة مثل هذه.